Nicolás Pablo Müller



I am currently a post-doctoral researcher at the Laboratoire de Physique de l'École Normal Supérieure (LPENS) in Paris, France. My scientific work is focused on theoretical and numerical studies of magnetic reversals in geodynamo. By means of high-resolution direct numerical simulations, I explore how the presence of a stably-stratified layer below the core-mantle boundary affects the reversal process.

I am also interested in the properties of two- and three-dimensional quantum turbulent flows. My main studies focused on the differences and similarities of the intermittent behavior in classical and quantum turbulence using velocity circulation statistics.

Personal Details

- Date of Birth: 23 August 1994
- Nationality: Argentina / Switzerland
- Professional address: 24 Rue Lhomond, 75005 Paris, France

Experience

Laboratoire de Physique de l'ENS

Paris, France

Nice. France

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER September 2023 - Ongoing

• Magnetic reversals in geodynamo with a stably-stratified layer.

Observatoire Côte d'Azur

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER February 2023 - August 2023

• Study of circulation statistics in two-dimensional classical and quantum turbulence.

Education

PhD in Physics Nice, France

OBSERVATOIRE DE LA CÔTE D'AZUR - SUPERVISOR: GIORGIO KRSTULOVIC

2019 - 2022

2014 - 2019

Buenos Aires, Argentina

• Thesis Title: Quantum vortices, statistics of velocity circulation and excitations in superfluid turbulence

Licenciatura in Physics Science (equivalent to Master of Science in Physics)

University of Buenos Aires

- (Equivalent to) MS.c Thesis: Critical transition between 2D-3D flows in quantum turbulence 2018-2019
- (Equivalent to) BS.c Thesis: Design and construction of a robust illumination system for SPIM Microscopy 2017

Prices_

Thesis Prize Nice, France

UNICA FOUNDATION - EDSFA • Best thesis of 2022 of the Fundamental and Applied Science Doctoral School (EDSFA)

Reviewer for scientific journals _____

American Physics Society

- Physical Review Letters
- · Physical Review B

Participation in international conferences _____

Bridging Classical and Quantum Turbulence

ORAL PRESENTATION

• Title: Are 2D classical and quantum turbulence equivalent? Insights from velocity circulation statistics.

26th Rencontre du non-linéaire

ORAL PRESENTATION

28 - 30 Mars 2023

Cargèse, France

4 - 14 July 2023

Paris, France

12 July 2021

Porquerolles, France 15 - 20 May 2022

Title: Vortex clustering, polarisation and intermittency of velocity circulation in quantum turbulence.

School on Nonlinearity, complex phenomena and universality for waves

Title: Anomalous scaling of velocity circulation in quantum turbulence.

Quantum Fluids School São Carlos, Brazil

POSTER PRESENTATION

20 February - 4 March 2022

• Title: Anomalous scaling of velocity circulation in quantum turbulence.

GDR Turbulence Paris-Saclay, France 27 - 29 October 2021

ORAL PRESENTATION

• Title: Intermittency of velocity circulation in classical and quantum turbulence.

WINE Conference Online

POSTER PRESENTATION 1 - 2 July 2021

• Title: Kolmogorov and Kelvin wave cascades in quantum turbulence.

UK quantum fluids webinar series Online

ORAL PRESENTATION • Title: Intermittency of velocity circulation in quantum turbulence.

24th Rencontre du non-linéaire Online

POSTER PRESENTATION 24 - 26 March 2021

• Title: Intermittency of velocity circulation in quantum turbulence.

StatPhys 27 Buenos Aires, Argentina

ORAL PRESENTATION 8 - 12 July 2019

• Title: Critical transition between 2D-3D flows in quantum turbulence.

Publications

- [1] N. P. Müller and G. Krstulovic. Exploring the equivalence between two-dimensional classical and quantum turbulence through velocity circulation statistics. arXiv:2306.17735 (2023).
- N. P. Müller, Y. Tang, W. Guo, and G. Krstulovic. Velocity circulation intermittency in finite-temperature turbulent superfluid helium. *Physical Review Fluids* **7**, 15 (2022).
- N. P. Müller and G. Krstulovic. Critical velocity for vortex nucleation and roton emission in a generalized model for superfluids. *Physical Review B* **105**, 014515 (2022).
- J. I. Polanco, N. P. Müller, and G. Krstulovic. Vortex clustering, polarisation and circulation intermittency in classical and quantum turbulence. *Nature Communications* **12**, 7090 (2021).
- N. P. Müller, J. I. Polanco, and G. Krstulovic. Intermittency of Velocity Circulation in Quantum Turbulence. Physical Review X 11, 011053 (2021).
- [6] N. P. Müller and G. Krstulovic. Kolmogorov and Kelvin wave cascades in a generalized model for quantum turbulence. Physical Review B 102, 134513 (2020).
- N. P. Müller, M.-E. Brachet, A. Alexakis, and P. D. Mininni. Abrupt Transition between Three-Dimensional and Two-Dimensional Quantum Turbulence. Physical Review Letters 124, 134501 (2020).
- B. Moretti, N. P. Müller, M. Wappner, and H. E. Grecco. Compact and reflective light-sheet microscopy for longterm imaging of living embryos. *Applied Optics* **59**, D89–D94 (2020).

Skills_

Languages

- Spanish (*Native*)
- English (Fluent in written and spoken)
- German (Intermediate)
- French (Intermediate)

Computational Fluid Dynamics: Parallel computing (OpenMP and MPI)

Programming languages: Python - Fortran - Julia - Matlab - ﷺX